Guide to the William Dowdell Denson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Audiovisual Materials, 1918-2004; Series V
  - Photographs
    - Notebooks
      - "A Gentleman in the Devil's Court"
        - "Personal", 1998, undated (Box 29, Folder 23)
        - "Dachau", 1945-1946, undated (Box 29, Folder 24)
        - "Mauthausen", 1946, undated (Box 29, Folder 25)
        - "Buchenwald", 1947, undated (Box 29, Folder 26)
        - "Press Photos", 1945, undated (Box 29, Folder 27)
      - "Dachau Photos", [1945], undated (Box 29, Folder 28)
      - Flossenbürg Trial Photos, [1946], undated (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Videotapes
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - Cablenews 12 interview, 1990 May 7 (Box 30)
    - Museum of Jewish Heritage interview, 1990 October 23 (Box 31)
    - ABC interview, 1991 January 24 (Box 32)
    - Interview with Huschi Denson regarding William Denson
      - Original, 1992 March 12 (Box 33)
      - Duplicating master, 1992 March 12 (Box 33D)
      - Use copy, 1992 March 12; 1 (Box 33U)
    - United States Holocaust Memorial Museum interview, 1994 August 25 (Box 34–36)
    - "The Liberation of Dachau," Drew University Holocaust Study Conference, 1994 November 10 (Box 37–38)
    - Simon Wiesenthal Center candle lighting ceremony, 1995 January 1 (Box 39)
      There is no sound on the recording.
    - Personal home video for Denson from his colleagues at the law office, 1995 December 24 (Box 40)
    - Interview at Denson's law office about legal aspects of the war crimes trials, 1997 September 23 (Box 41)
    - NBC news story about Denson, 1998 May 31 (Box 42)
    - "William Denson: Champion of Human Rights", undated (Box 43)
    - Channel 12 obituary for Denson, undated (Box 44)
  - Audiotapes
    - Bondy, Lance, 2001 February 15 (Box 45)
    - Guth, Paul, 2001 February 24 (Box 45)
      - Original cassettes [4 tapes; restricted] (Box 46–49)
      - Use copy cassettes (Box 46U–49U)
    - Lippe, Meltzer, 2002 March 20 (Box 50)
    - Surowitz, Solomon, 2002 March 25 (Box 51)
    - Haulot, Arthur, 2002 June 1 (Box 52)
  - DVD: Justice At Dachau The Trials of an American Prosecutor [cannot be reproduced; for reading room viewing only], 2004 (Box 53)